The epic conclusion of the Jurassic era.
Jurassic World Dominion is a adventure, action, science
fiction film directed by Colin Trevorrow.
Four years after Isla Nublar was destroyed, dinosaurs now
live—and hunt—alongside humans all over the world.
This fragile balance will reshape the future and determine, once and for all, whether human beings are to
remain the apex predators on a planet they now share with history's most fearsome creatures.
Owen Grady, played by Chris Pratt.
Claire Dearing, played by Bryce Dallas Howard.
Ellie Sattler, played by Laura Dern.
Alan Grant, played by Sam Neill.
Ian Malcolm, played by Jeff Goldblum.
Kayla Watts, played by DeWanda Wise.
Jurassic World Dominion is a 2022 American science fiction action film directed by
Colin Trevorrow, who co-wrote the screenplay with Emily Carmichael.
It is the sixth installment in Jurassic Park franchise, concluding the
original storyline that began with Jurassic Park (1993).
Chris Pratt, Bryce Dallas Howard, BD Wong, and Omar Sy reprise their roles from the previous films, along with Laura
Dern, Jeff Goldblum, and Sam Neill, who appear together for the first time since the original Jurassic Park.
Also joining the cast were DeWanda Wise and Mamoudou Athie.
The film is set four years after the events of Jurassic World: Fallen Kingdom, with dinosaurs and
other de-extinct prehistoric animals now living alongside humans around the world.
It follows Owen Grady and Claire Dearing as they embark on a rescue mission, while Alan Grant, Ellie
Sattler and Ian Malcolm work to expose a conspiracy by the genomics corporation Biosyn.
Planning for the film began in 2014, before the
release of the first Jurassic World film.
Filming took place from February to November 2020 in Canada, England, and Malta.
With an estimated budget of up to $465 million, it is one
of the most expensive films ever made.
Because of the COVID-19 pandemic, filming was suspended for
several months and the release was delayed by a year.
Jurassic World Dominion premiered in Mexico City on May 23, 2022, and was
released in the United States by Universal Pictures on June 10.
It received generally negative reviews from critics, although an extended
edition, included with the home media release, was met more positively.
Like its predecessors, the film was a financial success and grossed $1 billion
worldwide, becoming the third-highest-grossing film of 2022.
A standalone sequel, Jurassic World Rebirth, was released on July 2, 2025.
The film explores themes of paleontology, giant
monster, sequel, survival, dinosaur.
The tone is thought_provoking.